<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>works on helene</title><link>/works/</link><description>Recent content in works on helene</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coding da Vinci</title><link>/works/coding-da-vinci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/coding-da-vinci/</guid><description>CC BY-SA 3.0 DE Coding da Vinci &amp;#183; Source Coding da Vinci is a programme that promotes collaboration and free knowledge sharing in the field of cultural heritage. We seek to democratise relationships between museums, archives, libraries and the public towards open dialogue and co-creation practices.
Coding da Vinci brings cultural institutions together with dedicated people from design and tech communities to develop ideas and prototypes for the cultural sector and for the public.</description></item><item><title>Datenschule</title><link>/works/datenschule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/datenschule/</guid><description>Public domain/ CC0 1.0 von Nationaal Archief &amp;#183; Source While data becomes increasingly available, civil society organisations are struggling to build capacity to work with data and understand alleged or factual risks.
Datenschule (School of Data Germany) seeks to help non-profit organisations and activists to understand and use data responsibly in order to increase their impact on existing societal challenges. The programme offers hands-on data training and empowers non-profit organisations to build evidence-based campaigns with dedicated data practitioners and community members.</description></item><item><title>JedeSchule</title><link>/works/jedeschule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/jedeschule/</guid><description>Public domain/ CC0 1.0 &amp;#183; Source JedeSchule.de (Every School) explores the accessibility of school information made available by the Statistical Offices of Germany’s federal states. It is an information and research platform that advocates for more transparency within the educational system.
This project provides an overview of more than 30.000 schools across 16 federal states along with comprehensive statistics and analysis of out-of-school activities, school partnerships and budget spending.</description></item><item><title>Offenes Parlament</title><link>/works/offenesparlament/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/offenesparlament/</guid><description>OffenesParlament (Open Parliament) provides information on the work of the German Bundestag, its policy amendments and interesting debates led by MPs.
With this campaign we advocate for more transparency in political decision-making and better public access to information held by state institutions.
The project takes a closer look at the plenary protocols of the 18th legislative period (2013 - 2017) published by the Bundestag and reflects upon selected political discussions of that time, such as same sex marriage, the Syrian conflict and the Volkswagen emissions scandal.</description></item><item><title>StoryHunt</title><link>/work/storyhunt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/work/storyhunt/</guid><description>Public domain/ CC0 1.0 &amp;#183; Source The StoryHunt: Uncover the EU was a training programme designed to develop and apply the skills needed to find interesting stories in financial data. With the StoryHunt we offered an opportunity to practice the necessary skills in a supportive peer-to-peer learning environment.
Together with my colleagues from Datenschule, OpenBudgets.eu, and SubsidyStories.eu, we invited journalists, non-profit organisations, developers and designers to dive into a massive database of the European Union’s primary financial instrument, the ESIFunds.</description></item></channel></rss>